Guide to the Virginia Science & Technology Campus records, 1990-2022 RG0159
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Virginia Science & Technology Campus records
1987-2022
1991-2020
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Patterson, Tara
RG0159
4 Linear Feet
This collection contains historical documents, floor plans, departmental information, promotional materials, strategic planning, memos, staff meeting notes, operating procedures, budgets, statistics, annual reports, document delivery materials, collection development information, academic coordinator meeting notes, WRLC information, Gelman Library policies, course instruction materials, and training and orientation guides pertaining to the Virginia Technology & Science Campus. These materials date from 1987-2022, with the bulk of materials dated between 1991-2020.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Tara Patterson, 2021 (Accession 2021.036).
Biographical / Historical
George Washington University opened its Virginia Science and Technology Campus in 1991. Located in Loudoun County, the campus provides flexible formats for bachelor's degree completion programs, master's degrees, doctoral degrees, and certificates. The campus began with just one building, Exploration Hall, and has since expanded to include 7 buildings across 122 acres of land. The collection documents some of the original plans for the campus and University Center, as well as information related to the campus library. The materials include a variety of administrative documents and paperwork, such as statistical reports, budgets, and promotional materials.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: Planning and Construction, Library Records. Series 2 Library Records is further divided into 3 subseries.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains historical documents, floor plans, departmental information, promotional materials, strategic planning, memos, staff meeting notes, operating procedures, budgets, statistics, annual reports, document delivery materials, collection development information, academic coordinator meeting notes, WRLC information, Gelman Library policies, course instruction materials, and training and orientation guides. These materials date from 1987-2022, with the bulk of materials dated between 1991-2020. The records document the planning and operations of the Virginia Science & Technology Campus at George Washington University.
Campuses; Education; Continuing education; George Washington University -- Students; George Washington University. Virginia Science and Technology Campus; Patterson, Tara
- Planning and Construction, Series 1
  - Library Signs, undated; RG0159 Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Floor Plans, 2003; RG0159 (Box 10, Item 2)
- Library Records, 1987-2020; 1991-2014; Series 2
  Arrangement
  Series is organized into three sub-series: Historical Documents, Strategic Planning, and Administration; Budgets, Statistics, and Annual Reports; Outreach, Reference, and Instruction.
  Scope and Contents
  Materials in this series include historical documents, floor plans, departmental information, promotional materials, strategic planning, memos, staff meeting notes, operating procedures, budgets, statistics, annual reports, document delivery materials, collection development information, academic coordinator meeting notes, WRLC information, Gelman Library policies, course instruction materials, and training and orientation guides from the Virginia Science & Technology Campus Library staff files. These materials date from 1987-2022, with the bulk of materials dated between 1991-2020.
  - Historical Documents, Strategic Planning, and Administration, 1989-2012; RG0159 Series 2
    Sub-series is organized by original order.
    Materials in this sub-series series include historical documents, floor plans, departmental information, promotional materials, strategic planning, memos, staff meeting notes, operating procedures, and general administrative information about the Virginia Science & Technology Campus Library. These materials date from 1989-2012.
    - VA Campus Info, 1991-2005; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Other VSTC Departments, 2000-2020; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Historical and Promotional Materials [1/2], 1992-2006; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Historical and Promotional Materials [2/2], 1992-2006; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - VSTC Library Relocation Building 2 Floor Plans, 2002-2005; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Historical Gelman & VCL Items, 1991; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - VCL Early History/Librarian Documents, 1992-1994; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Work Procedures, Computer Terminology, Ordering Process, & Acquisitions Workflow, 1989-2004; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Memo, 1991; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Middle States Accreditation, 1996; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - VCL Newsletters & Performance Appraisal, 1993-1994; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Gelman & VCL Newsletters, 1991-2000; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Staff Meetings, 1993-1999; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Offsite (WRLC) Shelving, 1994; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Gelman Library System Employee Guide [1/2], 1999-2004; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Gelman Library Stystem Employee Guide [2/2], 1999-2004; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - User Education Library Tours, Presentation, 1990-2009; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - First Search, 1993; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Evaluation, undated; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - IPEDS Survey, 1992; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Focus Group & Photo Release Forms, 2005-2008; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Strategic Plan/VCL, 1995-2012; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Academic Excellence Initiative [1/2], 2001-2003; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Academic Excellence Initiative [2/2], 2001-2003; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Budgets, Statistics, and Annual Reports, 1991-2014; RG0159 Series 2
    Materials in this sub-series series include budget documents, document delivery information, collection development materials, annual reports, and statistics related to the Virginia Science & Technology Campus Library. These materials date from 1991-2014.
    - 1996 Budget, RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - 1996/7 Budget, 1996-1997; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - 1997-8 Budget, 1997-1998; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Budget '98 - '99, 1998-1999; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Budget/FY 2000, RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Budget FY 2002, RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - FY 03, 2003; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - FY '05, 2005; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - FY 2006, RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Budget FY '07, 2007; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - FY '08, 2008; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - VCL Budget, undated; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - VS & TCL Budget Reports FY 2012, RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Collections Budgets Past Years, Budget - VCL 2013, VSTC Budget FY14, 1992-2014; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Document Delivery, undated; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Collection Dev, undated; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - VCL Collections - Journals, undated; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Annual Report, 1993-1997; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Annual Report, 1997-2002; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Annual Report, 2003; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Annual Report, 2003-2004; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Document Delivery, 1991-1993; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - VCL Annual Stats 96-97, 1996-1997; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Statistics [1/2], 1998-2004; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Statistics [2/2], 1998-2004; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Statistics FY '03, 2003; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Statistics, 2001-2006; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Statistics & Document Directories, undated; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Pilot Project Statistics, undated; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Book Use Report [1/2], 2001-2004; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Book Use Report [2/2], 2001-2004; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Outreach, Reference, and Instruction, 1987-2020; RG0159 Series 2
    Materials in this sub-series series include Academic Coordinator Meeting materials, WRLC information, Gelman Policies and Organization, Course Instruction processes, Academic Department information, Training and Orientation materials, and Programming information from the Virginia Science & Technology Campus Library. These materials date from 1987-2020.
    - Academic Coordinator's Meeting [1/2], 1994-2001; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Academic Coordinator's Meeting [2/2], 1994-2001; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - WRLC, 1994-2004; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 3 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Gelman Policies & Org., 1988-2003; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 3 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - OCLC, 1987-1994; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 3 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Library Newsletters, 1991-1997; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 3 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Remote User Ed, undated; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 3 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Library General Information & Services, undated; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 3 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - HRD [Human Resource Development] [1/2], 1990-2003; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 3 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - HRD [Human Resource Development] [2/2], 1990-2003; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - HRD [Human Resource Development] Courses, 1997-2006; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - EMBA [Executive Master of Business Administration], 1993-1997; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Engineering, 1990-1996; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - MSIST [Master of Science in Information Systems Technology] Fall '13, 2013; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - NCAC, 1992-1994; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Nursing, 2008-2014; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Nursing [1/2], 2010-2013; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Nursing [2/2], 2010-2013; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Pharmacogenomics, 2004-2013; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Corporate Liaison Program [1/2], 1991-2007; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Corporate Liaison Program [2/2], 1991-2007; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - FCCC Items, 2008-2020; RG0159 Series 2 Sub-Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 6)